# Nguyễn Hoàng Đỗ Uyên

# **Data Analyst**

(+84) 334.382.642 - nguyenhoangdouyen@gmail.com - Linkedin Profile

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

Having over two years of experience in **FMCG and E-commerce**, developing strong business acumen through Trade and Commercial roles with an **analytical mindset** and a passion for uncovering insights behind numbers. Currently transitioning into Data Analytics by proactively upskilling and refining analytical capabilities to **drive business growth** through data-driven strategies.

# WORKING EXPERIENCE

## **ADA ASIA - CLIENT: UNILEVER**

#### Commercial Associate (Full-time)

Jan 2024 - Sep 2024

- Analyzed platform metrics and managed performance trackers to identify sales trends and enhance promotion effectiveness, contributing to a **20% uplift in sell-out in H1 2024.**
- Optimized e-merchandising and promotion tools, ensuring comprehensive visibility compliance to enhance visibility and drive conversions.
- Led campaign execution on Lazada consist of managing listings, pricing, and promotions, maintaining **Top 1 Homecare ranking for OMO** in all 2024 Mega Campaigns.

### **FRIESLANDCAMPINA**

## Channel & Category Development Assistant (Full-time)

Oct 2022 - Jun 2023

- Managed 7 types of reports, providing insights for MT Channel to assess promotions and optimize trade strategies for higher ROI.
- Implemented trade marketing activities (scheme creation, memo deployment, system setup), **ensuring 99% accuracy** in promotion execution and sales orders.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to execute in-store activities, organize display contests, and manage NPD listings, which contributed to the successful launch of **Dutch Lady Cereal Polybag**, **surpassing sell-out targets with 104%** in 1,500 BHX stores and 160% in 125 WCM stores.

## **ABBOTT LABORATORIES**

### Trade Marketing Intern (Full-time)

Apr 2022 - Oct 2023

- Collected and analyzed pricing, promotion, and visibility data from market visits to support trade planning and reduce stock-out risks.
- Coordinated shopper activation and POSM development, ensuring quality, smooth rollout, and brand visibility. Managed in-store activation for **Similac, Abbott Grow, and PediaSure, boosting sell-out by 30%** through sampling and PG consultation

PROJECTS VIEW MORE MY PROJECT

#### 1. Ecommerce Web Performance & Purchase Behavior Analysis | SQL, BigQuery - View Project

- Uncovered key e-commerce patterns, including customer behavior insights and web performance trends by cleaning and extracting data from Google Analytics dataset (~1M rows, 12 months) in BigQuery.
- Analyzed customer behavior, purchase trends, and key metrics using **aggregate functions, window functions, JOINS, and subqueries** to validate business hypotheses and uncover insights on transaction rates and user engagement.

## 2. Sales Performance & Market Expansion for A Retail Global Superstore | Power BI - View Project

- Processed and integrated over **50k sales orders** from 3 separate CSV with **Power Query**, cleaning and transforming the data, then performed data modelling to support analysis.
- Applied Design Thinking to create an interactive Power BI dashboard, calculated key metrics with **DAX**, and designed visualizations to highlight trends. Provided data-driven recommendations to support market expansion and optimize product selection.

## 3. Customer Segmentation for Marketing Campaigns in a Global Retail Superstore | Python - View Project

- Performed customer segmentation using an automated RFM scoring model in Python on ~541 K rows of Super-Store transactional data over 1 year.
- Applied **RFM Model** with quintile-based scoring to segment customers, uncovering insights into their behavior. Visualized customer segments and trends over time, providing insights to optimize Marketing campaigns for retention and revenue growth.

# **SKILLS**

**Technical Skills: SQL** (JOINS, CTEs, Aggregate Function, Window Functions), **Python** (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn), **Power BI, Basic Statistics & Analytics** (Hypothesis Testing, SPSS, AMOS), **Machine Learning** (Classification, Clustering).

Soft-skills: English, Time-management, Collaboration, Critical Thinking, Adaptability

# **EDUCATION**

**UEH University** 2019 - 2023 - Bachelor of Commercial Business - **GPA: 3.59/4** 

Achievement: UEH500 Excellent Assignment Awards 2022.

Certification: TOEIC 725 (IIG Vietnam), IC3 (IIG Vietnam), Data Coaching 1:1 (Unigap)